Triangle Shirt Waist Company Legal Documents 6036/033
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Triangle Shirt Waist Company Legal Documents
1911-1981
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Triangle Shirt Waist Company
6036/033
2.42 cubic feet
2.4 linear ft.
Records.
5770058
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 10, 2011
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 17, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
5770058
- National Consumers League, George C. Bean and Novelty Silk Shop Inc. against Triangle Waist Company, 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Trial documents
- My Memories as a Worker in the Notorious Triangle Waist Company Factory in New York City, Beginning in 1906 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Emergency Relife after the Washington Place Fire, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Report of the Red Cross Emergency Relief Committee of the Charity Organization Society of the City of New York
- Triangle, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Screenplay by Naomi Foner, first draft
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Transcript, pages 1-150; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Transcript, pages 151-300; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Transcript, pages 301-450; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Transcript, pages 451-600; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Transcript, pages 601-672; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Transcript, pages 1212-1350; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Transcript, pages 1351-1500; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Transcript, pages 1501-1650; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Transcript, pages 1651-1800; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Transcript, pages 1801-1901; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Transcript, pages 2053-2204, notes; copy 1.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Transcript, pages 1-125; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  Transcript, pages 126-250; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Transcript, pages 251-400; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Transcript, pages 401-550; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Transcript, pages 551-672; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Transcript, pages 1212-1350; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Transcript, pages 1351-1465; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  Transcript, pages 1755-1901; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Transcript, pages 2053-2123, notes; copy 2.
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 1 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Transcript
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 2 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 3 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 4 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 5 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- People of the State of New York against Isaac Harris and Max Blanck [reel 6 of 6], 1911 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 1 (Box 4)
  - Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 1 -- removed from bx 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Compact Disc
- Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 2 (Box 5)
  - Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 2 -- removed from bx 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 1 (Box 6)
  - Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 1 -- removed from bx 2 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 2 (Box 7)
  - Triangle Fire Tiffs, pt. 2 -- removed from bx 2 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Triangle Fire: Word docs, OCR docs (Box 8)
  - Triangle Fire: Word docs, OCR docs -- removed from bx 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Triangle Tiff 2 (Box 9)
  - Triangle Tiff 2 -- removed from bx 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)